thinkprogress.org 2007-02-09

# Privacy Policy - Center for American Progress Action Fund

_Last updated:   September 6, 2006_

The Center for American Progress Action Fund (CAPAF) is committed to protecting the privacy and security of both new and frequent visitors as well as our supporters and subscribers. Here is our online privacy policy for information collected through our website and through email lists.

The Center for American Progress Action Fund expects it may need to revise its privacy policy as it develops the features of its future site.  The American Progress Action Fund will make reasonable efforts to inform users of any changes, but the spirit of this policy will be maintained, and our policy not to sell, exchange, rent, trade, or give email lists to unaffiliated third parties will never be altered.

Use of the Center for American Progress Action Fund’s website is not restricted to registered users, and we expect to provide a robust experience to all users. 

If you have any questions about our privacy policy, please fell free to email us at: [action@americanprogressaction.org](mailto:action@americanprogressaction.org)

You can also reach us via US Mail at:  
Center for American Progress Action Fund, 1333 H Street, NW, 10th Floor, Washington DC 20005

**What the Center for American Progress Action Fund will do with your information:**

The Center for American Progress Action Fund will not sell or share the personal information you provide or that we collect through our website to any unaffiliated organization without your permission, with the following exceptions:  We may share personal information with third parties who provide services, such as website hosting or other services of an administrative or technical nature, solely for the purpose of providing such services and subject to confidentiality obligations.  In addition, we reserve the right to disclose personal information if we believe in good faith that such disclosure is required by law. 

From time to time, we may send you information from other like-minded organizations whose products or services we think subscribers might find interesting, but we do not exchange, trade, rent, or give email lists to unaffiliated third parties.

**If you sign up for one of our mailing lists:**

The Center for American Progress Action Fund is committed to providing timely updates to our users by email.  We will request information from you to enhance our ability to customize our communications with you so you get the information you want.  We will collect relevant contact information and enable you to self-select the type of information that you’d like to receive. You will be able to unsubscribe from communications you receive from us by following the directions included in each such communication.

**If you submit information to public areas of an CAPAF site:**

Please be aware that if you decide to disclose personally identifiable information on a publicly-accessible area of an CAPAF site (such as thinkprogress.org), this information may become public.  CAPAF does not control the acts of other visitors to its sites, so please be cautious when deciding to reveal personal information on a public area of any site.  Please contact us if you believe a visitor to an CAPAF site is improperly collecting or using information about you or other users.

**If you contribute money online:**

The Center for American Progress Action Fund appreciates and will accept online contributions. Users will be asked to submit contact information for verification purposes.  Your contact information will also be added to our email list, from which you can unsubscribe by following the instructions included in each email you receive from us. Financial information will be transmitted to third-parties only for the purpose of processing your donation, and will not be stored by the Center for American Progress Action Fund.

**Cookies:**

A cookie is a small piece of information that a website can store on a computer and later use to recognize a user.  A purpose of  cookies is to enhance your ability to receive the information you want.  The Center for American Progress Action Fund may use session cookies to enhance the experience of users.  A session cookie expires when a user closes the browser in which the Center for American Progress Action Fund’s website was viewed.  As with all cookies, users can personalize their browser settings to reject session cookies.

**IP Addresses and Log File Data:**

IP addresses are ID numbers for the location of your computer or network on the internet.  Log files are recordings of the traffic to and from a server.  The Center for American Progress Action Fund’s servers log IP addresses for systems administration and troubleshooting.   We track page hits in the aggregate to track the popularity of pages that people visit.  With that information we can improve the quality of the site.

**Children's privacy:**

The Center for American Progress Action Fund is concerned about the safety and privacy of children online.  Because of this, we will make all efforts to comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA). COPPA and its accompanying FTC regulations establish United States federal law that protects the privacy of children using the Internet. We do not and will not knowingly contact or collect personal information from children under 13. Our site is not intended to solicit information of any kind from children under 13, and we will develop our site with the capacity to block acceptance of information from children under 13 whenever age-related information is requested.

It is possible that by fraud or deception by others we may receive information given to us or pertaining to children under 13. If we are notified of this, as soon as we verify the information, we will immediately obtain parental consent or else delete the information from our servers. If you want to notify us of our receipt of information by children under 13, please do so by e-mailing us at [action@americanprogressaction.org](mailto:action@americanprogressaction.org)

**Security:**

CAPAF has measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of visitor personally identifiable information that is under our control.  For example, only select CAPAF staff and contracted individuals have access to personally identifiable information provided by visitors to non-public areas of our site.  We use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving sensitive personal and financial data from our site.  Please note, however, that security breaches can occur even if reasonable steps are taken to prevent such breaches; for example, we cannot guarantee that information provided through our sites will not be illegally accessed on our servers or intercepted while being transmitted to us over the Internet.  Please contact us if you believe there has been any breach of the security of an CAPAF site. 

**Please Note:**

The Center for American Progress Action Fund plans to regularly update and add new features to our website.  Because of this, the Center for American Progress Action Fund expects to revise its privacy policy as its site develops.  Such amendments will be posted in the privacy policy section of the site.  You can determine whether the privacy policy has been modified since your last visit by checking the “Last updated” legend at the top of the policy.  As stated above, the spirit of this policy will be maintained, and our policy never to sell, exchange, rent, trade, or give email lists to unaffiliated third parties will never be altered. The Center for American Progress Action Fund links to other like-minded websites, but is not responsible for the content or the privacy policies of those websites.
